A Guide to the Theodore Malinin collection of Alexis Carrel and Charles Lindbergh papers FA208
Rockefeller Archive Center
Theodore Malinin collection of Alexis Carrel and Charles Lindbergh papers
1905-1992, 1910-1945
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Malinin, Theodore I.
Carrel, Alexis
Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles August)
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA208
7.6 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
Theodore I. Malinin (1933- ) was a physician and professor of orthopedics and rehabilitation at the University of Miami's School of Medicine since 1969. He is best known in the medical community for his work on the science of preservation in regards to donated bone and tissues, and for his direction of the University of Miami Tissue Bank which he founded in 1970. Motivated by an article in Science magazine about the forgotten contributions of Dr. Alexis Carrel to the surgical field, Malinin set forth on a path of research that eventually culminated in 1979 with the publishing of Malinin's Surgery and Life: The Extraordinary Career of Alexis Carrel.
Alexis Carrel, born in France in 1873 joined the staff of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (RIMR) in 1906 where he remained until his retirement in 1939. Winner of the Nobel Prize in Physiology and Medicine in 1912 for his work on vascular suturing, Carrel focused much of his research at RIMR on the study of tissue culture and organ transplantation. After retirement Carrel returned to France where he died in 1944.
Malinin acquired most materials in this collection whilst compiling information for Surgery and Life. The materials were acquired from the Alexis Carrel Collection at Georgetown University, as well as friends and colleagues of Carrel, such as Charles A. Lindbergh (with whom Carrel developed the perfusion pump). The collection includes material on Carrel as well as his work with Lindbergh and other colleagues at RIMR, and Malinin's papers on Carrel.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Scope and Contents note
This collection is one of the Rockefeller University Special Collections.
Includes Malinin's book on Carrel, as well as books that were either formally Carrel's or mentioned Carrel, that have been removed from the collection and can be found in the library.
Arrangement note
Arranged in alphabetical and chronological order.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I.650-5
Conditions Governing Access note
The collection is open for scholarly reserch.
Related Materials
The Alexis Carrel papers collection is available at Georgetown University, Special Collections. Please consult an archivist for an inventory of the holdings at Georgetown.
Biology -- Research; Biochemistry; Tissue culture; Medical education; Medical care; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Blood-vessels -- Surgery; Heart, Mechanical; Physiology; Medicine, Preventive; Life sciences; Medical sciences; Medical research; Blood; Malinin, Theodore I.; Carrel, Alexis; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles August); Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University
- Carrel Biographical, 1902-1967; 1; 0.2 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes biographical information related to Alexis Carrel as well as recollections of Carrel and his work as written by friends, colleagues and others; bibliographical information of Carrel's published works; newspaper and magazine clippings related to Carrel's published works and research; and obituaries of Carrel in both French and English.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Carrel Biographical: Biographic Notes from a History of RIMR (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Carrel Biographical: Biographic Notes (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carrel Biographical: Biography by G.W. Corner (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carrel Biographical: [Carrel Bibliography], folder 1 of 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carrel Biographical: [Carrel Bibliography], folder 2 of 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Carrel Biographical: [Carrel Bibliography], folder 3 of 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carrel Biographical: Carrel Collection (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Carrel Biographical: Coudert - Address to the Century Associates (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Carrel Biographical: CV's and Biographies (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Carrel Biographical: Decorations (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Carrel Biographical: Dr. Carrel's Notes from a Book on Canada, by, C. Muller, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Carrel Biographical: Dr. Carrel's Home Floor Plan (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Carrel Biographical: Ebeling - Carrel's Immortal Chicken Tissue (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Carrel Biographical: ["Further Correspondence with the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the Treatment of British Prisoners of War and Interned Civilians in Germany"], 1916 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Carrel Biographical: Georgetown University Alumni Association Magazine, Winter, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Carrel Biographical: D. Gibson - Soc. NY Hospital - Carrel's Method for the Treatment of Wounds - War Hospital, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Carrel Biographical: J.J. Gillon (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carrel Biographical: New York Times & Harpers publicity for Man, the Unknown, 1937 February 22 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carrel Biographical: Newspaper and Magazine Articles (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Carrel Biographical: [Newspaper Clippings] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Carrel Biographical: [Newspaper Obituaries] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Carrel Biographical: [Obituary (in French)] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Carrel Biographical: Obituary - by Dr. Simon Flexner, folder 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Carrel Biographical: Obituary - by Dr. Simon Flexner, folder 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Carrel Biographical: Operation Techniques (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Carrel Biographical: [" Remembering Alexis Carrel & Charles A. Lindbergh"- By Theodore Malinin] (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Carrel Biographical: The Rotary Club of New York's Tribute to A. Carrel - Haire, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Carrel Biographical: Science (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Carrel Biographical: The University of the State of NY - Bulletin to the Schools, 1937 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Carrel Biographical: [WWI Newspapers] (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Carrel Files, 1901-1945; 2; 2.2 Cubic Feet
  Broken into subgroups: Annual Reports; Correspondence; Man, the Unknown; and Manuscripts. The first subgroup contains annual reports of Carrel and his colleagues while at RIMR. The correspondence contains letters, telegrams, receipts, pamphlets, and other materials that were sent to Carrel from family, friends, colleagues and others, as well as letters sent from Carrel.
  Includes both original letters and xeroxed copies. Man, the Unknown contains newspaper clippings and publicity announcements about Carrel's book by that title, as well as correspondence to and from Carrel about the book. Within the manuscript subgroup are both published and unpublished manuscripts by Carrel.
  Includes both originals and xeroxed or retyped copies of the manuscripts.
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports, 1909-1932 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports, 1917 1919 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports, 1918-1935 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports, 1920 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports - Mousery Reports, 1931 1933 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Carrel Files: Annual Reports - Cultivation of Whole Organs, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1901-1905 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, de Martigny, 1904-1936 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1904-1936 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1904-1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Carrel's Colleagues - Cushing, Beck, etc., 1905-1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Mr. Joseph Carrel (Dr. Carrel's brother), 1905-1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1906-1907 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1906 1912 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Anti-vivisection & Laboratory Procedures, 1906-1912 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Halsted, 1906-1922 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - C. Beck, 1906-1941 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Castrillo, 1907; folder 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - George Stewart, 1907; folder 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - R.I.M.R., 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - R.I.M.R., 1907-1911 1936-1942 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Herter NY, 1907-1912 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Ruth Perry Bowes, 1907-1912 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - NY, 1907-1913 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Pierre de la Motte, 1907-1920 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Le Riche, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1908; folder 1 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1908; folder 2 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1908; folder 3 of 3 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Dr. Theodore Tuffier, 1908-1932; folder 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Tuffier, 1908-1940; folder 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Flexner, 1909-1935 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Burrows, 1910 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1911; folder 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1911; folder 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Flexner, 1911-1933 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Nobel Prize Correspondence, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1912; folder 1 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1912; folder 2 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1912; folder 3 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1912-1913 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1912-1914 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Dr. Dakin, 1912 1917 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - H. James - Manager - R.I.M.R., 1912-1926 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - [R.I.M.R], 1912-1939 1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - de Martigny, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Carrel - Personal, 1913-1914 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - NY, 1913-1914 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - R.I.M.R., 1913-1918 1930 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Dr. Mayo, 1913-1924 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Noguchi, 1913-1928 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1913-1935 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1913-1940 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Miss Crutcher, 1913-1945 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1914; folder 1 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1914; folder 2 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1914; folder 3 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1914-1919 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Flexner, 1914-1934 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Carrel's correspondence dealing with his work, 1914-1937 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1914-1940 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1915-1920 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1916-1917; folder 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1916-1917; folder 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - WWI, 1916-1919 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Flexner, 1916-1940 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917; folder 1 of 8 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917; folder 2 of 8 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917; folder 3 of 8 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917; folder 4 of 8 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917; folder 5 of 8 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917; folder 6 of 8 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917; folder 7 of 8 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917; folder 8 of 8 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Halsted, 1917-1919 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Dr. Corwin, 1917-1926 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917-1927 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1917-1939 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1918-1920 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Flexner, 1918-1940 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - WWI - Mission de Noisiel, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Dr. Bernoud, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - C.C. Guthrie, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - WWI, 1919 1929 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1919-1935 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - R.I.M.R., 1919 1931-1940 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - H. Cushing, 1919-1936 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Radium in France, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1920; folder 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1920; folder 2 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1920 1933 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1920 1927-1933 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1921-1930 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - [Carrel Telegrams], 1921-1937 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Rufus Cole, 1921-1938 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - House, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Maximow, A.-Ringer's Solution, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - [Personal], 1923 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1923-1926 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Peyton Rous, 1923-1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - [Personal], 1924 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1925 1939 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1925-1939 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1928-1935 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1930-1931; folder 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1930-1931; folder 2 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Carrel's Collaborators, 1930-1940 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Euge Meyer, 1930-1940 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Mr. de la Mairie, 1930-1943 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1931 1935 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - R.I.M.R., 1931-1935 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Dakin Solution, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Interviews, 1935-1938 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1935-1939 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Man, the Unknown, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Dr. Gasser, 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Retirement from Rockefeller Institute, 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - J.E. Hoover, 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Schmieden, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Miss Crutcher, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1939; folder 1 of 3 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1939; folder 2 of 3 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1939; folder 3 of 3 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - The Last Days, 1939-1945 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - France, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Carrel Signatures, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence- (A - Al), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (Am - Az), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (B - Bl), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (Bm - Bz), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (C - Carr), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (Carri - Cl), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (Cm - Cz), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (D - Dl), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (Dm - Dz), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (E - Ez), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (F - Fl), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (Gm - Gz), 1940 [1938-1939] (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - (H - Hl), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1940-1944 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - American Legion, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Personal, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - WWII, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Madame Carrel - Finance, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1944-1945; folder 1 of 3 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1944-1945; folder 2 of 3 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence, 1944-1945; folder 3 of 3 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Carrel Files: Correspondence - Miscellaneous. Letter, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Carrel Files: Man, the Unknown, 1935-1938 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Carrel Files: Man, the Unknown, 1935-1939 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Carrel Files: Man, the Unknown.; "Lecture for the Cosmopolitan Club", 1936; folder 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Carrel Files: Man, the Unknown.; "Lecture for the Cosmopolitan Club", 1936; folder 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Carrel Files: Man, the Unknown, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Carrel Files: Man, the Unknown.: S-Z, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Carrel Files: Man, the Unknown - "New Preface", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Carrel Files: Man, the Unknown, 1943-1945 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Mechanism of the Decline and Resumption of Cell Activity, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1922 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1923-1924 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Lecture - Staff Meeting, 1927 December (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - The Fundamental Characteristics of the Fibroblasts and the Microphange, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Measurement of Age, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Tissue and Organ Culture, 1928 1935 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Le Mode de Locomotion des Cellules des Tissues et du Sang Etudié par la Cinématographie, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Artificial Regeneration of Nerves, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Mechanism of the Formation and Growth of Malignant Tumors, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - "Significance of Death" - Delivered at Academy Medicine, NY - December, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Organ Culture, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - The Making of Civilized Man, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Part I: Life - Part III: Sleep, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Muncie, Indiana Address, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1937; folder 1 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1937; folder 2 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1937; folder 3 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1938; folder 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1938; folder 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Conservation of Human Resources, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1939; folder 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, 1939; folder 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts - Essay on Hitler (holograph), 1940 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Carrel Files: Manuscripts, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Experiment Files, 1906-1940; 3; 1.8 Cubic Feet
  Contains charts, graphs, tables, drawings and notes. Experiments related mostly to tissue culture studies particularly related to Sarcoma and fibroblasts. Also contains some of the experiments completed by Carrel's colleagues and associates, most notably Dr. Ebeling. Materials related to the Mousery at the RIMR also included.
  - Experiment Files: Action of Adult Chicken Muscle Juice on the Rate of Growth of Homologous Fibroblasts (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Experiment Files: Action of Adult Guinea Pig Muscle Juice on the Duration of Life of Chicken Fibroblasts (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Experiment Files: Action of Adult Rabbit Spleen on the Rate of Growth of Fibroblasts (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Experiment Files: Action of Foreign Sera on the Growth of Fibroblasts (Cat) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Experiment Files: Action of Foreign Sera on the Growth of Fibroblasts: Comparison between Chicken and Cat Serum (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Experiment Files: Action of Foreign Sera on the Growth of Fibroblasts: Comparison between Serum of Young (6 months) and Old (10 years) Dog. Serum Concentration: 5%, 10%, 15%, and 20% (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Experiment Files: Action of Foreign Sera on the Growth of Fibroblasts: Comparison between Young and Old Cat Serum (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Experiment Files: Action of Foreign Sera on the Growth of Fibroblasts (Dog) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Experiment Files: Action of Juice from Rabbit Bone Marrow (Adult) on the Rate of Growth of Chick Fibroblasts (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Experiment Files: Action of Pilocarpine (Box 7, Folder 10)